Sometimes I feel like all those stars shining up there.
I float in the middle of the immensity.
I am an unsolved equation in
the middle of the vacuum.
An island of solitude in a constellation in the making.
Have you ever felt that way?
I mean, felt that there is
something bigger than you.
I would like to be part of this world, like each
of the stars that punctuate the sky.
I would like to gather what is divided
within me to brighten my nights.
However, I have exiled myself from my center
and I gravitate around myself to try to understand
who I am.
Maybe I am only the fragments of what I have been,
of what is and of all that will be.
And even if there will only be one
moment like that, I try to remember it.
But it always ends up escaping me.
Time, on the other hand, continues to pass tirelessly.
In my neighborhood.
Other lights resist the darkness.
They pierce through windows
enlightened.
Behind every window.
I guess there's a life.
I guess there's a heartbeat, a secret.
A moment that no one else will ever see.
Some may be waiting for a call, having fun or studying.
Some sell a piece of their lives on screen
while some love, separate or break up.
Still others are just trying to survive the night.
And even if I sometimes meet those who live behind these
windows, I often ignore the worlds that coexist next to mine.
Have you ever wondered what are these worlds that
exist inside your building, your street, your city or even inside
of you?
In each of us, there is a story.
I would like to get closer to these stories and the people around me.
And the more night gives way to day, the more
I listen to what the silence tells me.
How I would like to understand everything that
separates us as much as what unites us.
So, one morning,
I left.
I've been walking for a long time.
I have crossed countries and continents.
I redrew my internal borders
until I touched the edge of the world.
On my way.
I have moved forward.
I grew up.
I lived.
I dreamed.
I stumbled.
I discovered.
I loved.
I suffered.
I learned.
I felt very strongly in my chest and my whole body.
I got drunk again and again with the
dawn breaking, the ponds, the blue,
the landscapes, the springs and the faces.
And in one of them,
I met my gaze.
I was different.
I had the same lines.
I spoke another language, but I understood it.
I recognized my joys, my wounds, my hopes and my struggles.
I saw myself as I was for the first time.
Facing myself,
I met I.
I continued on my way.
I went home and started to inhabit my life.
I am behind my window and I observe the life that goes by
in front of me.
The tilt of time never ceases to pass and the
hours seem to stretch to make way for the present.
Each second becomes a burst of the
unexpected, a wonder suspended in the
midst of those who continue to move within me.
As the sun continues its course, daylight
draws changing shapes, with constantly renewed contours.
She makes the pearls of dew sparkle on the branches.
It revives colors and warms
my face.
I grasp this moment as a fragment of eternity.
And in this fragment, there is perhaps our common history.
We are all part of this world, like each of
the stars that punctuate the sky.
We contain black holes and
suns, multitudes and endless horizons.
We are expanding universes.
We form constellations
in motion.
We are connected and rewrite history at every moment.